We have talked about individual process models but we haven't yet talked
個々のプロセスモデルについてお話しましたが 運転手が行おうとする
about how to maintain some beliefs about which behavior the driver intends to perform.
行動についての信念を維持する方法についてはまだです
This is the role of multimodal estimation algorithms.
これはマルチモーダル推定アルゴリズムの役割となります
A simple approach to multimodal estimation is called
マルチモーダル推定への簡単なアプローチは
autonomous multiple model estimation or AMM.
自律的複数モデル推定 (AMM) と呼ばれます
While describing AMM, I will use
AMM の説明においては 後でリンクを貼る論文で
the same notation that is used in a paper which I will link to later.
使用されているものと同じ表記法を使用します
The variable M represents the number of process models or
変数 M はプロセスモジュールまたは行動の数で
behaviors and each variable mu represents the probability of behavior.
各変数 mu は行動の確率を表します
To understand how these probabilities are computed,
これらの確率が計算される方法を理解するために
let's go back to our T intersection example.
T 字路の例に戻ってみましょう
Let's say we have two process models here.
ここに 2 つのプロセスモデルがあるとします
One to go straight and one to turn right and they both have Gaussian uncertainty.
1 つは直進 1 つは右折するものです いずれもガウス分布の不確実性があります
Let's say that we observe this state for the vehicle at time k minus one and we observe
時間 k - 1 のときに車両のこの状態を観測し
this state for the vehicle at time k. In order to
時間 k のときに車両のこの状態を観測するものとします
compute the new probabilities for the behaviors based on the new observation,
新しい観測に基づいて行動の新しい確率を計算するために
we will run our two process models for
時間 k - 1 の状態から開始して 1 ステップの間
one step starting from the state at time k minus one.
2 つのプロセスモデルを実行します
When we do this,
これを行うと
we get these two expected states for time k. If we just look at what
時間 k の間にこれら 2 つの推定状態が得られます
the distribution on the vehicle's s coordinate looks
2 つの推定状態について車両の s 座標での分布が
like for the two expected states, this is what we see.
どうなっているか見ると このようになります
Where the red curve gives the probability density function of S for turning right,
ここで赤色の曲線は右折の確率密度関数 S を表し
the blue curve represents going straight
青色の曲線は直進を表します
and the observation at timestep k is somewhere here.
時間ステップ k での観測はこのあたりです
We can see that this observation is substantially more
この観察では 直進よりも
consistent with turn right than it is with go straight.
右折とかなり一致していることがわかります
This is measured by the likelihood of the observation as
これは 各モデルについての観測の尤度によって
for each model and the probability of
測定されます 各行動の確率は
each behavior is a function of these likelihoods
これらの尤度と 前のタイムステップで
and of the probabilities computed in the previous timestep.
計算された確率の関数です
The important quantity for the AMM is
AMM の重要な量は
the ratio of these likelihoods after they get multiplied by the previous probability.
前の確率によって乗算された後のこれらの尤度の比率です
The equation ends up looking like this,
方程式はこのようなものになり
where this term is the probability of model I
この項はタイムステップ k のときのモデル i の確率です
at timestep K. This term is the probability of
この項はタイムステップ k - 1 のときの
model I at timestep K minus one and
モデル i の確率で この L 項は
this L term is the likelihood of the observation at time K for that model.
そのモデル i の時間 k のときの観測の尤度です
The denominator just serves to normalize our probabilities so that they all sum to one.
分母は 確率をそれらすべてが合計 1 になるように正規化する役割をしています
M, in this situation would be two since we are only considering two maneuvers.
この状況で M は 2 つの操作のみを検討しているので 2 となるでしょう